<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.sarahlturner.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.sarahlturner.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-07-18T14:07:04+01:00</updated><id>https://www.sarahlturner.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sarah Turner</title><entry><title type="html">The NHS COVID-19 App…and tech solutionism</title><link href="https://www.sarahlturner.com/blog/2021/nhs-app/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The NHS COVID-19 App…and tech solutionism" /><published>2021-07-18T09:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-07-18T09:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.sarahlturner.com/blog/2021/nhs-app</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.sarahlturner.com/blog/2021/nhs-app/">&lt;p&gt;The more eagle-eyed amongst you may have noticed from my CV that I studied a master’s in public policy, specialising in digital technologies, not all that long ago.  And since then, I have been acutely aware of the tendency of digital technologies to be thrown at problems that have much wider, much more complex, issues at their core.  Overweight? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.standard.co.uk/news/health/nhs-overweight-fitbits-and-supermarket-discounts-b944859.html&quot;&gt;Give them a fitness tracker&lt;/a&gt;! Workforce required to work at home? &lt;a href=&quot;https://metro.co.uk/2021/01/18/one-in-five-firms-linked-to-spying-on-staff-as-they-work-from-home-13925783/&quot;&gt;Spyware can help you track their every move&lt;/a&gt;! Got a pesky issue to solve with border controls? &lt;a href=&quot;https://internationalfinance.com/blockchain-in-the-irish-border-saga/&quot;&gt;BLOCKCHAIN&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue that’s come to the forefront today is the role of contact tracing apps in our exit from Pandemic Times.  In the UK, we have had a shoddy track record of almost every aspect of managing this pandemic…from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldometers.info/coronavirus/country/uk/&quot;&gt;well over 100k deaths&lt;/a&gt;, to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-56319927&quot;&gt;very questionable procurement&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.sky.com/story/covid-19-expired-ppe-stock-covered-over-with-new-dates-while-one-box-was-full-of-insects-mps-told-12156956&quot;&gt;totally unusable PPE&lt;/a&gt;, to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bmj.com/company/newsroom/uks-response-to-covid-19-too-little-too-late-too-flawed/&quot;&gt;locking down too late over and over again&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last week, many of us here are struggling to reconcile news that there may be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/06/covid-cases-rise-above-100000-a-day-sajid-javid-concedes-england&quot;&gt;100k infections a day over the summer&lt;/a&gt; whilst we “unlock” completely.  This means that - even for those of us who have no pre-existing health concerns, and that are fully vaccinated - we are very likely to have significant disruption brought to our lives, with people we rely on falling sick, maybe getting sick ourselves, our children falling sick - and having to isolate. In the UK, contact tracing has two major routes: the Test and Trace service that physically calls up/contacts people who have been named by positive cases, and the COVID-19 App, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://inews.co.uk/news/technology/nhs-covid-app-how-work-self-isolate-test-and-trace-change-explained-1094798&quot;&gt;monitors users’ close contact with others on an anonymous basis&lt;/a&gt;. If you get “pinged” (as we now seem to be calling it) by either, you will be told to isolate for up to 10 days (depending how speedy the testing process has been for the positive person).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, over the last week, the penny seems to have dropped in relation to the app.  An increase in people testing positive means an increase in the likelihood of getting “pinged” by the NHS COVID-19 app in particular, if you’re out and about and getting on with your life (with each positive case seeming to generate 4 or 5 pings on average).  This app, which took a while to get off the ground, and has always been eyed with suspicion (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/blog-post/security-behind-nhs-contact-tracing-app&quot;&gt;despite it working on privacy preserving technology&lt;/a&gt;) is now going to be causing problems for a different reason: it’s &lt;em&gt;working as expected&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what happened? Did this cause a flurry of concern that people would just stop using it? Well, yes.  Did this then cause those determining the policy to rethink &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; people might stop using it? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/health-and-families/coronavirus-nhs-app-contact-trace-b1884131.html&quot;&gt;Well…not really&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People were, I think, happy to use the app whilst there was the mutual understanding that they were doing something for the government/the public, and the government were working to keep them safe with restrictions. But now restrictions are set to end, a number of things are being realised, all of which stem from the use of the app as too fundamental a part of remaining COVID policy. This is what Evgeny Morozov referred to - all the way back in 2013 - as &lt;em&gt;technological solutionism&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Very often self-tracking solutions are marketed as ways to address a problem. You can monitor how many calories you consume; monitor how much electricity you are consuming. It sounds nice in theory but I fear a lot of policymakers prefer to use the self-tracking option as an alternative to regulating…or engaging in more structural reforms…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This quote taken from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2013/mar/09/evgeny-morozov-technology-solutionism-interview&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What seems to be happening in the UK is a general unravelling in the trust of this powerful piece of technology - because its correct application is becoming utterly unworkable without ongoing efforts to suppress the virus.  People are discovering that moving freely around, when the virus is also moving freely between people, will cause the app to do the job it is supposed to. This means that - as seen in the last week - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/16/summer-chaos-predicted-as-16m-in-england-told-to-isolate-in-a-week&quot;&gt;half a million people got an alert that they should self-isolate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And many of those people then discovered that there is no legal requirement to isolate if you are told to do so by the app alone (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/guidance/nhs-test-and-trace-how-it-works&quot;&gt;and not a phonecall from Test and Trace&lt;/a&gt;). So what, you might ask? Why wouldn’t you self-isolate if you’re told? Isn’t that the point of the app?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, that’s obviously the intention.  But, in a society that has opened up, where individuals may be adhering to their moral compass, they might quickly find that adhering to a non-legally binding obligation comes with significant costs.  Insurance (travel or otherwise) may not cover the need to cancel or rebook if you are pinged by the app, &lt;a href=&quot;https://inews.co.uk/inews-lifestyle/travel/british-holidaymakers-lose-thousands-pinged-nhs-covid-app-legal-loophole-1108721&quot;&gt;because it is not legally binding&lt;/a&gt;.  Similarly, employers cannot access government payment schemes for furlough for workers told to isolate by the app, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mlothianmclean/status/1413428830962847744&quot;&gt;because it is not legally binding&lt;/a&gt;. Adherence to the app may have always been the preserve of those who could afford to &lt;a href=&quot;https://faq.covid19.nhs.uk/article/KA-01116/en-us&quot;&gt;install it on a new-enough phone&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-55259272&quot;&gt;self-isolate&lt;/a&gt;, but now this is playing out on a truly national level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app should not be deployed without appropriate policy to ensure people - and those they work for (or with), or care for - are not disadvantaged for following it in the way that they have been told they should.  This, of course, echoes the unending calls from groups such as Independent Sage to make &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.independentsage.org/category/fttis/&quot;&gt;meaningful isolation payments&lt;/a&gt; so that people are incentivised to do the right thing and stay home when they need to. It also echoes the calls from countless groups representing the vulnerable, parents, carers, those who cannot work from home…&lt;em&gt;children&lt;/em&gt;…that you cannot have a functioning society without wide-ranging policy that protects those who cannot protect themselves, or those they have a responsibility to protect. Policy to keep people safe (paid isolation, quick turn around times for test results and functioning track and tracing, mask wearing are the obvious ones), and not just compliant at their own significant expense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is just not an app for all of that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="society" /><category term="NHS app" /><category term="public policy" /><summary type="html">The more eagle-eyed amongst you may have noticed from my CV that I studied a master’s in public policy, specialising in digital technologies, not all that long ago. And since then, I have been acutely aware of the tendency of digital technologies to be thrown at problems that have much wider, much more complex, issues at their core. Overweight? Give them a fitness tracker! Workforce required to work at home? Spyware can help you track their every move! Got a pesky issue to solve with border controls? BLOCKCHAIN!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Who’s watching Netflix? A letter to Airbnb hosts</title><link href="https://www.sarahlturner.com/blog/2020/airbnb/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Who’s watching Netflix? A letter to Airbnb hosts" /><published>2020-08-07T10:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-08-07T10:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.sarahlturner.com/blog/2020/airbnb</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.sarahlturner.com/blog/2020/airbnb/">&lt;p&gt;A number of my friends - myself included - have found themselves renting cottages and flats this summer, in an attempt to have a break at home, rather than a hotel stay abroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really common to find a smart device or two in these rental properties. Or at the very least…a wi-fi connection.  Hosts are in a tricky place here: would you go and stay somewhere without wi-fi? I wouldn’t. But…does that mean that I want to have an Alexa or log into a Smart TV?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some thoughts about how hosts could balance the desire for nice shiny tech with the fact that they suck up so much information about those who use them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-tell-your-guests&quot;&gt;1 Tell your guests&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.co.uk/help/article/887/what-are-airbnbs-rules-about-security-cameras-and-other-recording-devices-in-listings&quot;&gt;Airbnb’s rules about security cameras and other recording devices in listings&lt;/a&gt; say that you have to tell your guests if you have a surveillance device in your home. They list security cameras, nannycams, even smartphones. It doesn’t explicitly mention voice controlled assistants or smart TVs (both of which do have microphones and/or cameras in). So, at the very least, mention there is tech in your property in your listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-turn-it-off&quot;&gt;2 Turn it off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conjunction with 1 - make sure smart devices are switched off when a new guest arrives.  It shouldn’t be up to your guests to discover there’s an Alexa listening to them just in case they need it to make fart sounds or tell them the weather.  It should be up to them to decide they want to use it and to switch it on actively….and linked to this…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-log-it-out-or-create-house-accounts&quot;&gt;3 Log it out (or create house accounts)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IoT/smart devices are not currently very well designed for multiple users.  They often require specific users to log in and all the data collected will be as if just that one person (or few people associated with the account) is generating it all.  You should want your guests to log in with their own accounts. And then to log out again when they leave (you should check for this after they leave, and log them out without hesitation OR snooping). Or, in certain cases (like Smart TVs), you might want to consider whether to create an account for the TV for whichever streaming services are available - providing, of course, you have paid relevant taxes and tariffs (in the UK, for example, the Licence Fee), and it is allowed under the Terms of Service of the streaming service you’re using.  And if you do set up a house account, delete the data associated with it regularly (and change the password - which should be unique - regularly too).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-change-your-router-password-after-every-guest&quot;&gt;4 Change your router password after every guest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t do this, everyone that ever stays in your property will be able to log into the wi-fi when they can pick it up on a device (inside or out). Most people wouldn’t think twice about this, which makes it…not ideal. Change the password regularly. Ideally after every guest, but otherwise regularly (monthly, say).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-do-you-really-need-it&quot;&gt;5 Do you really need it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some devices that could be really beneficial for your stay. Wi-fi is necessary, sure….but is a voice assistant? What do people really use it for? Will they miss it if it’s not there? Are there devices you could set up where guests could use a guest mode instead of connecting directly (such as a Chromecast instead of a full-on smart TV)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6-if-you-do-really-need-it&quot;&gt;6 …if you do really need it…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you decide you do really need it, maybe consider putting together a very straight-forward walk through document for guests, telling them how they can use the device (particularly how to log in and out), how they can delete their data, and how they can use the device without logging in (if that’s possible).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got any other thoughts? &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:slt41@kent.ac.uk&quot;&gt;E-mail&lt;/a&gt; me if there’s something I’ve missed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="society" /><category term="personal" /><category term="devices" /><category term="security" /><summary type="html">A number of my friends - myself included - have found themselves renting cottages and flats this summer, in an attempt to have a break at home, rather than a hotel stay abroad.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Better than before? Reflections on transferring life online</title><link href="https://www.sarahlturner.com/blog/2020/online-conferences/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Better than before? Reflections on transferring life online" /><published>2020-06-25T10:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-06-25T10:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.sarahlturner.com/blog/2020/online-conferences</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.sarahlturner.com/blog/2020/online-conferences/">&lt;p&gt;As with so many others, I have found myself, since March, doing everything through my laptop and phone. In some respects this has been daunting - in others, really liberating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve attended two online conferences in the last week; four in the last month or so. I do video calls for meetings that would have ordinarily been face to face (or, weirdly, would have been just phone calls), and my daughter knows how to message and video call her friends through the school instance of Teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been considering what I’ve found helpful, and difficult, about these times, as we start to open up again. What has been better than before, in terms of attending conferences online?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pros&quot;&gt;Pros&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flexibility&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - I have two small children and a husband with a real job.  I am also a migraine sufferer, and they seem to be triggered by travelling. Being able to have a conference beamed to my laptop is really helpful in many respects. Recordings are very helpful in those instances where synchronicity isn’t realistic at my end, for whatever reason.  I can listen to things live, or at a time when I can concentrate - the two don’t often overlap.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inclusivity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - The reduced costs of online conferences means that I can plan to attend more of them &lt;em&gt;and still afford to do my research!&lt;/em&gt; It also means I can, as above, attend at my own pace - and in my own space, not the other side of the world, which minimises disruption to my dependents.  I can also watch videos that have been pre-recorded carefully in advance - often with captioning, which is obviously of value. I can dip in and out, and have the opportunity to engage with more sessions than I would have if I had to be physically present.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Proving it is possible&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - I have worked from home for a day or two a week for many years.  It’s just…helpful. If you find it easy, and not too distracting, it saves money, reminds you that you are more than an employee - you are an employee with laundry and a house that needs cleaning! - and saves significant time from the commute.  I know both employees and employers who deny that it is possible to do anything useful from home. This is just wrong for many people, and, hopefully this period will provide a reset, for those who want or need it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everything sticks to time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - I am yet to attend a conference session that overruns, or a session where people use the Q&amp;amp;A for “less of a question, more of a comment” style ramblings. These are unequivocally excellent things.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cons&quot;&gt;Cons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zoning out&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Working from home has always been good for multitasking. Which means that it can be terrible for…concentrating on one thing well.  Which is less than ideal for long video sessions that don’t necessarily require a lot of input.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who are you, again?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - I am an introvert.  If I never had to introduce myself to anyone ever again, I would be ok with that.  But I have found online conferences are hard, if not impossible, to use for anything other than dissemination of knowledge. Even smaller breakout sessions can feel very overwhelming from a participation point of view, if you don’t know anyone else, or are worried about appearing on camera or a flaky internet connection.  Networking may have to evolve…online reading groups, anyone?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Exclusivity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - What, Sarah? You just said it was inclusive! Yes…it is…until it isn’t.  I have had some discussions about my charity’s annual conference, and my weird fixation throughout was data costs.  I have a lovely office…with a spotty Internet connection.  I have upped my phone data allowance twice since March to deal with needing to stream video meetings.  Not everyone has the budget to do that. Or a device. Or even a safe space to attend such meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;When it goes wrong…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - It is pretty stressful.  If you can’t find a meeting room in an office, you can probably find someone who can point you in the right direction. If your meeting link doesn’t work…what do you do? In my case, try the same link or login process periodically, and hope you didn’t miss anything vital. When it goes really wrong (Zoom bombing, I’m looking at you), it is overwhelming and disturbing as a guest - and terrifying as a host.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="society" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">As with so many others, I have found myself, since March, doing everything through my laptop and phone. In some respects this has been daunting - in others, really liberating.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What resources have helped you so far?</title><link href="https://www.sarahlturner.com/blog/2020/resources/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What resources have helped you so far?" /><published>2020-06-17T12:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-06-17T12:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.sarahlturner.com/blog/2020/resources</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.sarahlturner.com/blog/2020/resources/">&lt;p&gt;I recently had to fill in an application for something.  I was asked to provide a list of a few resources that had inspired me to do the research I’m doing now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the most fun I’ve had in a long time, and feels like the &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; way to explain to anyone who’s interested in how I think about my research, and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here’s the list. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Podcasts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have often told people I started getting interested in digital technologies and society because of podcasts.  They usually look at me with a mixture of alarm, amusement and fear. But that’s because they’ve not heard these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wnycstudios.org/podcasts/notetoself&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;Note to Self&lt;/a&gt; on a flight back home from Sydney.  I basically listened to it for a day straight.  It considers all aspects of technology and society - with topics ranging from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wnycstudios.org/podcasts/notetoself/episodes/escape-yahoo-verizon&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;portability&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wnycstudios.org/podcasts/notetoself/episodes/dark-web-opioid-epidemic&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;dark web&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wnycstudios.org/podcasts/notetoself/episodes/kid-photos&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;sharenting&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wnycstudios.org/podcasts/notetoself/episodes/different-kind-streaking&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;tech ethics&lt;/a&gt;. The various &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wnycstudios.org/podcasts/notetoself/projects&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;projects&lt;/a&gt; that the podcast undertook - learning how to be bored; how to control your personal data - all very eye-opening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gimletmedia.com/shows/reply-all&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;Reply All&lt;/a&gt;. I am a Reply All evangelist. That’s all I can say other than apologise for how often I talk about it.  It’s a podcast about technology and society and everything and anything.  There is, honestly, a Reply All episode for everything. However, in terms of my research, they cover all manner of cyber security issues in incredibly engaging ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I particularly recommend:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gimletmedia.com/shows/reply-all/v4he6k&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;The Snapchat Thief&lt;/a&gt; to learn about how to use multifactor authentication, and protecting your online privacy;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gimletmedia.com/shows/reply-all/z3hler&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;The Russian Passenger&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://gimletmedia.com/shows/reply-all/rnhoww&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;What Kind of Idiot Gets Phished?&lt;/a&gt; to listen to how confusing a data breach can be, and how easy it is to fall for a well-crafted phishing attempt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gimletmedia.com/shows/reply-all/dvhe6l&quot; target=&quot;\_blank&quot;&gt;The Secret Life of Alex Goldman&lt;/a&gt; to begin to understand the threat of spyware to the vulnerable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cyber security resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my Master’s year, resources such as the Electronic Frontier Foundation’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://ssd.eff.org/en&quot;&gt;Surveillance Self-Defense&lt;/a&gt; tools and Motherboard’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/d3devm/motherboard-guide-to-not-getting-hacked-online-safety-guide&quot;&gt;Guide to Not Getting Hacked&lt;/a&gt; were the most valuable resources to help me really understand how cyber security – and particularly threat modelling – is a personal endeavour that requires significant knowledge and thought, even when systems are appropriately designed to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Designing for all&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.penguin.co.uk/books/111/1113605/invisible-women/9781784706289.html&quot;&gt;Invisible Women&lt;/a&gt; by Caroline Criado Perez to everyone I meet. It is incredible to note how little of what has been designed for everyday life has been done so alongside the lived experience of all who use the product.  This can lead to truly terrible results (in medicine, or health and safety, for example), but also has really profound implications for almost any digital technology product that is sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have recently also read Marika Cifor and Patricia Garcia’s paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1145/3364685&quot;&gt;Gendered by Design: A Duoethnographic Study of Personal Fitness Tracking Systems&lt;/a&gt; – a dual ethnography of fitness tracking from the point of view of the two female researchers.  This paper underlines the point that situations where differences between users are superficially touched upon make it worse than if they had been ignored.  The examples given in this paper include devices assuming that all those identifying as women menstruated. Having made that assumption, and despite taking no details of the menstrual cycle, the device then provided one researcher with a tip to combat “pre-menstrual symptoms” – at a time when it was entirely irrelevant to her. It doesn’t take much to destroy a relationship with a device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Researching in interesting ways&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have loved reading some of the more experimental methods of research undertaken in relation to the Internet of Things within the home.  Papers such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1145/2818048.2819954&quot;&gt;A Day in the Life of Things in the Home&lt;/a&gt; (Crabtree &amp;amp; Tolmie, 2016) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10606-018-9314-4&quot;&gt;“What do you want for dinner?”&lt;/a&gt; (Hyland et al., 2018) have really made me realise that there needs to be more than simply interviews and surveys as a means of getting to grips with how devices work in the home.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="society" /><category term="security" /><category term="design" /><category term="methods" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">I recently had to fill in an application for something. I was asked to provide a list of a few resources that had inspired me to do the research I’m doing now.</summary></entry></feed>